we've got round sprinkles why not long
我们已经有了圆润的点缀 为什么不会很久
sprinkles it'll be more interesting and
洒在上面会更有趣
it'll enable us to uh learn some new
这将使我们能够呃学到一些新的东西
techniques about blender which is what
关于搅拌机的技术是什么
this whole series is about so first
这整个系列都是关于第一个
things first we need to uh model those
首先 我们需要对这些东西进行建模
sprinkles so let's move to the left here
所以让我们移到左边
and uh we want to add an object we
呃 我们想要添加一个对象 我们
haven't mentioned it before but when you
以前没提过 但当你
add an object it's going to put it at
添加一个要放置它的对象
your 3D cursor and your 3D cursor is
您的3D光标和3D光标是
that thing that weird little thing
那个东西那个奇怪的小东西
little Crosshair at the bottom there
底部有个小十字准线
that's your 3D cursor and uh yeah I
那是你的3D光标 呃 是的 我
don't know blunder has a 3D cursor maybe
我不知道大块头可能有3D光标
other applications don't it's going to
其他应用程序不会 它将会
put it there and if you don't want it
把它放在那里 如果你不想要
there you can move that 3D cursor
在那里 您可以移动3D光标
somewhere else by hitting shift and
在其他位置按下Shift键并
right clicking and you can see it's now
点击鼠标右键 你可以看到它现在
moved it and actually attached it to the
已将其移动并实际附加到
plane which is where we would want it if
这就是我们想要的飞机 如果
you don't have a mouse do get a mouse
你没有鼠标 一定要买个鼠标
but in the interim you can also use the
但在此期间 您还可以使用
the uh cursor tool and that'll do uh the
呃 光标工具 这样就可以 呃
same thing all right so we're adding
同样的事情 好的 所以我们要添加
long sprinkles so obviously the object
长长的喷洒如此明显的物体
that we want to add is shift a mesh it's
我们想要添加的是移动一个网格
the cylinder okay too big by default so
默认情况下 气缸太大了 所以
let's change click this little thing
让我们改变一下 点击这个小东西
bring this up change the radius all the
把这个拿出来 改变所有的半径
way to its lowest and the depth all the
一路走到它的最低点和深度
way to its lowest as well and the
也跌到了最低点
vertices that's the uh like the
像这样的顶点
resolution right oh we'll fix that in a
解决方案对哦 我们会在一个
sec um the resolution it' be way too
秒 嗯 决议 这也是办法
high at 32 to be scattered on an object
高达32以散布在对象上
so let's set this to 12 and that'll be
所以我们把这个设置为12 那就是
just enough that it won't look Jagged
只要不让它看起来参差不齐就够了
and it'll look smooth okay great now I'm
它看起来会很光滑 好的 很好 现在我
going to move this up just so it's above
我要把这个往上移 这样它就在上面
the plane Zed okay now this problem that
飞机好了 现在这个问题是
you have if you go in too far it
如果你走得太远 你会有的
disappears the reason for that is that
消失的原因是
uh blender has a clipping start value
呃搅拌机有一个剪裁起始值
and because we're working at such a
因为我们工作在这样一个
small small scale we've got sprinkle
小的 小的 我们有撒在地上的
sized things now um it's too small and
现在大小的东西 嗯 它太小了
it's clipping it out so if you hit n and
它会把它剪掉 所以如果你按下n和
go to your view tab the clip start value
转到您的视图选项卡中的剪辑开始值
there it's 1 cm by default drag it all
默认情况下为1厘米 全部拖拽
the way to the left and it's now a
向左走的路 现在是
millimeter and it will have fixed that I
毫米 它会固定我
don't know why it's not the default like
不知道为什么不是像这样的默认设置
maybe somebody can tell me why is that
也许有人能告诉我为什么会这样
not the default value maybe there's a
不是缺省值可能有一个
reason but to me that would make sense
理性 但对我来说 这是有意义的
cuz then you never have this problem I
因为这样你就永远不会有这个问题了
don't know any disadvantages so anyway
不知道有什么坏处 所以不管怎样
we've got uh the base of a Sprinkle need
我们已经有了 呃 基本的需求
to make it long so tab into edit mode s
要让它变长 所以用Tab键进入编辑模式S
scale it Zed along the Z axis to
沿Z轴将其缩放为
elongate it and now we've got the rough
拉长它 现在我们就有了粗略的
length of a Sprinkle but how long is a
一滴水的长度 但有多长才是
Sprinkle there's no actual answer to
散播：没有实际的答案
that if you look at reference they are
如果你看一下参考文献 你会发现
all over the place the government
到处都是政府
evidently never stepped in and said like
显然从来没有插手说过这样的话
we're going to regulate it this is the
我们将对其进行监管 这是
the length of a Sprinkle this is the
洒水的长度这是
size of a spring I mean it's it's it's
弹簧的大小 我是说它是
the wild west out there they're doing
他们正在进行的狂野西部
crazy things so uh what that means as
疯狂的事情 所以 呃 这意味着
artists is we get to pick whatever is
艺术家们就是我们可以选择
most visually pleasing and I like the
最令人愉悦的视觉效果 我喜欢
ones which are more readable and to show
可读性更强、更易于展示的版本
you what I mean if we pull up two right
你什么意思 如果我们拉出两个正确的
this one on the left is like large
左边的这个像大号的
sprinkles right very like bold and then
非常大胆地向右撒 然后
one on the right here is like long thin
右边的一个就像长瘦一样
wispy ones that look like theyd get
那些看起来像他们会得到的细小的
stuck in your teeth and if we zoom out
卡在你的牙齿里 如果我们缩小
on this and then zoom out on this you
在这个上 然后缩小这个你
can see that the ones on the right tend
可以看到右边的那些倾向于
to kind of like the colors and
有点喜欢这些颜色和
everything just kind of blur together
一切都变得模糊了
and it just looks like a dut whereas the
它看起来就像个垃圾桶 而
one on the left the sprinkles are still
左边的一个还在洒水
readable so that's what we mean by
可读性 所以这就是我们所说的
readable and that's the one I like the
可读性好 这就是我喜欢的
most so we're going to go with some uh
大多数情况下 我们会选择一些呃
larger looking long sprinkles but you
看起来更大的长长的点缀 但你
can see that the sizes there's no
可以看到 这里没有尺寸
standard size because I think it's
标准尺寸 因为我认为它是
actually like it's from a Piping Bag at
实际上就像是从一个管子袋子里出来的
least if you make them at home but you
至少如果你是在家里做的话但你
can just pipe out icing and then when it
可以通过管道排出糖霜 然后当它
dries you just smash it up and it
变干了 你只是把它打碎了 它
becomes sprinkles um but yeah they they
变成了小水花 嗯 但是是的他们
just come out at any odd size so we got
只是出了任何奇怪的尺寸 所以我们有
long ones we got medium ones we got
我们有长的 有中号的
short ones and we've even got some curvy
短的 我们甚至有一些曲线
looking ones right these little like
看起来就像这些小家伙
like just slightly bsh looking ones so
就像是看起来有点像BSH的人
we're going to model small medium large
我们要把小型中型大型
and a bsh looking one and then we're
还有一个看起来像BSH的人 然后我们就
going to scatter that across the object
我要把它撒在物体上
so back in blender this is going to be
所以回到搅拌机 这将是
yeah let's this this will be the the
好的 来吧 这将是
short one uh okay but the end speaking
简短的 呃 好的 但是结束了
of which this end bit here uh it's a
它的这一端在这里 呃 它是一个
very sharp edge and even if we hit uh
非常锋利的边缘 即使我们击中了
shade smooth it's not going to solve it
遮阳板很光滑 解决不了这个问题
we want that like a rounded form to it
我们想要它像圆形一样
not this hor Blobby looking shape um
不是这个Hor Blobby看起来像嗯
because the reference again you can see
因为你再一次可以看到引用
oh it's another it's a different
哦 这是另一个 它是一个不同的
reference now is uh is a rounded shape
现在的指代是 呃 是一个圆形
all right so to create that rounded form
好的 要创建圆角形状
we're going to create a bevel and so I
我们要做一个倒角 所以我
want you to go into face select mode
我想让你进入脸部选择模式
okay which you can do by that so this is
好的 你可以这样做 所以这是
the faces right this is the edges if you
右边的面 这是边 如果你
go to Edge select mode and then this is
转到边选择模式 然后这是
the the face there so select the bottom
面在那里 所以选择底部
and the top face like that and then
上面的脸就像这样 然后
we're going to add a bell which will
我们要添加一个钟 它将
immediately become clear when you do it
当你做这件事时 立刻变得清晰起来
contrl B and now that we're in this
控制B 现在我们在这里
state as we pull out we can change the
当我们退出时 我们可以改变
the amount of the bevel and this is uh
斜面的数量 这是呃
you can see it's it's like yeah it's
你可以看到 它就像 是的 它是
just adding a 45° angle on that that
只是在上面加了一个45°的角度
corner there but if you scroll up it's
角落在那里 但如果你向上滚动 它是
going to add another level to it and if
将向其添加另一个级别 如果
you scroll up again it's going to add
您再次向上滚动 它将添加
another level to that so we can very
更上一层楼 所以我们可以非常
quickly create a rounded Edge to the
快速创建圆角边到
sprinkle uh you don't want to go too
撒吧 呃 你也不想去吧
much higher because again this is going
更高 因为这又是一次
to be scattered all over the donut you
散落在甜甜圈里的你
don't want to go too high poly so
不想走得太高 所以
that'll do so that's a simple bevel
这样就可以了 这是一个简单的斜面
operation and it's very common when
手术 这是非常常见的当
you're modeling so yeah contrl B is how
你在做模特 所以是的控制B就是这样
you do that all right so look at that
你做的很好 所以看看这个
we've got one sprinkle so now we need to
我们只有一滴水 所以现在我们需要
create three more so this is the small
再创造三个 所以这是小的
so let's go shift d and then X to just
所以我们先换d 然后换X
move it along the x-axis this is going
将它沿x轴移动 这是要运行的
to be the medium one so edit mode and
要成为媒体 所以编辑模式和
I'm going to go into toggle YF frame and
我将进入切换YF帧并
verticy select mode and now selecting
垂直选择模式 现在选择
the top part of the sprinkle hit G Zed
洒水的顶部击中了G Zed
and I'm going to move oops if you got
我要搬家了 如果你有
proportional editing turn that off g z
比例编辑关闭了gz
move that
把那个搬开
up okay that'll be the medium one yep
好的 那就是中号的 好的
and now shift d x move it along this is
现在按下Shift d x移动它 这是
going to be the long one so edit mode
将会是一个很长的编辑模式
and again g z move it up and this is
再一次把它往上移 这是
going to be the long sprinkle I don't go
将会是我不去的漫漫长路
too long maybe that long okay and then I
太久了 也许有那么久 好吧 然后我
want to make a bent sprinkle it's
想要做一个弯曲的洒水它是
slightly like curved so shift d x move
有点像弯曲的 所以Shift d x移动
it across and now with this one if I was
它穿过了 如果我是的话现在就是这个
to try to like curve this out there's
想要把这件事做得更好
not enough information here like if I
这里没有足够的信息 就像我
move that it's just a straight edge
动起来 这只是一条直线
there so if I want to make it curved I
所以如果我想把它弄弯的话
got to have more geometry there so like
一定有更多的几何图形 就像
we've done in the past crlr is how you
我们过去所做的CRLR就是这样的
create a loop cut so when you do that it
创建循环切割 以便在执行此操作时
says where do you want to put it I want
说你想把它放在哪里我想要
more than one though so I'm going to
不止一个 所以我要
scroll up till I get yeah just a bunch
向上滚动 直到我看到 是的 只有一堆
of Loops until I get what looks like squ
直到我得到看起来像是SQU的东西
square faces on those points somewhere
这些点上的方脸在某处
around that I don't want to go too high
在那里我不想走得太高
poly yeah like that what is that that's
Poly 对 就像这样 那是什么
in the bottom leftand corner eight eight
在左下角的88号
Cuts Okay click and then it's say way do
切好的 点击 然后它说方式做
you want to place it right click to
您要将其放置在单击鼠标右键以
cancel the movement so it places it
取消移动 以便将其放置
right in the center and
就在中间
now there we go okay now we've got this
现在我们开始了好的现在我们有了这个
one over here that is just long and
这里有一条又长又长
straight but low poly and this one same
笔直但很低的多边形和这一个一样
shape but High poly so to add a uh Bend
形状但是很高 所以要增加一个呃折弯
to it in previous tutorials I actually
在之前的教程中 我实际上
went into like edit mode and we did like
进入了喜欢编辑模式 我们确实喜欢
proportional editing and it was just
比例编辑和它只是
complicated and it actually didn't look
很复杂 实际上看起来并不像
great I've learned actually there's a
太好了 我了解到实际上有一种
modifier that'll do it very simply go to
修饰符可以非常简单地执行此操作
your modifier stack add modifier uh you
你的修改器堆栈添加修改器呃你
could find it inside here uh or you
可以在这里找到 呃 或者你
could search for it but it's the simple
我可以搜索它 但它很简单
deform uh modifier so add that and by
Deform Uh修饰符 因此添加该修饰符
default it is wrong so change it from
默认是错误的 因此将其更改为
twist to bend and look at that we've got
转身弯曲 看看我们得到了什么
our sprinkle ha and you can very easily
我们的撒布哈 你可以很容易的
whoops change the amount from a little
哎呀 把数量从一点点改变了
curve to a large curve and I think
弯成一条大曲线 我想
somewhere around the 30° Mark you will
在30度标志附近的某个地方 你会
notice though that it's it's like it's
但请注意 这就像是
bent more at this angle and that's
在这个角度弯得更多 这是
because it's bending it according to the
因为它是在根据
origin point so you see these little
原点 所以你可以看到这些
dots you might have wondered what they
你可能想知道它们是什么
are in blender that's called your origin
都在搅拌机里 这就是你的起源
point and it's used for a lot of things
它被用来做很多事情
like if you rotate an object you can see
就像如果你旋转一个物体 你可以看到
it's rotating from the point of that
它是从那个点开始旋转的
origin Point um like physics a bunch of
原点 嗯 像物理一样 一堆
things use the origin point the best way
事物使用原点是最好的方式
to think of it is like the center of
想想看 它就像
mass for the object so generally
物体的质量 所以一般
speaking as a rule of thumb you want it
凭经验来说 你想要它
to be in the center of the object and
位于对象的中心 并且
you can do it very quickly you select
你可以非常快地完成它 你选择
multiple objects you want to clear its
要清除的多个对象
uh origin Point shift select all of them
UH原点移位选择全部
and then right click and then say set
然后右击 然后说Set
origin origin to geometry and now you
几何体的原点 现在您
can see it's put it in the middle and
可以看到它被放在中间
now our curve is actually based on the
现在我们的曲线实际上是基于
uh starting in the middle which is what
呃 从中间开始 这就是
we want so y for us now I need to apply
我们现在想要的是Y 我需要申请
app this or else the next part it'll go
应用这个 否则下一部分就会发生
wonky so apply your simple to form so
摇摇晃晃的所以用你的简单形式
that it's actually uh yeah uh realized
它实际上是呃是的呃意识到了
onto the uh onto the mesh okay so going
放到 呃 放到网眼上 好的 继续
to your outline you can see we've well
从你的轮廓你可以看到我们做得很好
we started from humble beginnings but
我们从卑微的起点开始 但是
we've now got too much going on and it's
我们现在有太多的事情要做 这是
it's all starting to get a little bit
这一切都开始变得有点
chaotic so the way you organize things
杂乱无章 所以你的组织方式
in your outline and in blender generally
在你的轮廓里和搅拌机里
uh is uh you can group things together
呃 呃 你可以把东西组合在一起
um by creating collections so by default
UM通过创建集合 因此在默认情况下
we've actually got one collection
我们实际上有一套藏品
already just called collection but we
已经调用了集合 但我们
can create new collections by this
可以通过此创建新的集合
little button in the top right hand
右上角的小按钮
corner to create new collection um and I
角落来创建新的集合um和i
want to create it outside of our I mean
想要在我们的外部创造它 我是说
I don't actually know if we need like I
我不知道我们是否需要像我一样
don't know why it creates a collection
不知道为什么它会创建一个集合
for you for no I mean you could just
对你来说 不 我的意思是你可以
it's in the scene collection anyways I
无论如何 它在场景集合中 我
don't know if we actually need that one
不知道我们是否真的需要那个
um so we create a new collection just by
嗯 所以我们创建一个新的集合
hitting that and we can double click it
点击它 我们就可以双击它
to rename it to be whatever it is we
把它重新命名为无论它是什么
want so I'm going to call this sprinkles
想要 所以我要把这叫做洒水
okay um and because we have two types of
好的 嗯 因为我们有两种
sprinkles we have the sphere round
撒上我们让球体变圆了
sprinkle and then we have these long
撒上一层 然后我们就有这么长的时间
sprinkles I'm going to create two other
散布我要创造另外两个
um collections within this collection so
此集合中的UM集合 因此
hitting new again you can see it's
再次点击新的你可以看到它是
placed it underneath it and I'm going to
把它放在它下面 我要
call this one round and then clicking
叫这一轮 然后点击
sprinkles again I'll add another
再洒一次 我再加一次
collection and this one I will call long
收藏品和我称之为Long的这个
oh wait sorry this one long there we go
哦 等等 对不起 这个很长 我们走吧
okay so to move something to a
好的 所以要把一些东西移到
collection you can do it one of two ways
您可以通过以下两种方式之一来完成此操作
one you can select
一个你可以选择的
the uh the sphere which is the round
呃 就是圆形的球体
remember it's this little guy over here
记住 是这个小家伙在这里
the little tiny round sprinkle you can
小小的圆形喷头 你可以
just drag that into the uh that
只要把它拖到那个呃那个
collection and you can see it's now
收藏 你可以看到它现在
moved it there the other way is in your
把它移到那里 另一种方式是在你的
3D viewport if you select all of the
如果您选择了所有
objects that you want to move to a new
要将其移动到新的
collection hit M and it brings up this
收藏品击中了M 它带来了这个
and you just say move to the sprinkles
然后你只需说移到洒水处
long sub collection there we go and now
长子收藏 我们走了 现在
they're all moved there and now this one
他们都搬到那里去了 现在是这个
here if you wanted to give this a name
如果你想给它起个名字
you could um we got the camera we got
你可以 嗯 我们拿到相机了
the light we got the plane yeah you know
我们飞机上的灯是的 你知道的
what let's move our donut our donut and
让我们把我们的甜甜圈和甜甜圈
our icing let's move that to a new
我们的糖衣 让我们把它移到一个新的
collection as well so M and we can
收藏也是如此 所以M和我们可以
actually create a new collection from
实际上从创建一个新集合
the move uh options as well so I'm going
搬家 呃 还有其他选择 所以我要走了
to go new and let's call this do let's
去新的 让我们称之为Do 让我们
say Donuts cuz we're going to duplicate
说甜甜圈 因为我们要复制
and make more Donuts in the future so
在未来做更多的甜甜圈 所以
Donuts okay great so now this one here
好的 甜甜圈太棒了 现在这个在这里
has got the camera the light and the
已经拿到了相机 灯光和
plane so I'm going to do what I
所以我要做我想做的事
sometimes do with a scene is just call
有时候做一场戏就是呼唤
this one EnV which is for environment
这一个环境是为了环境
since this is a tutorial I'll actually
因为这是一个教程 所以我实际上
just type it out I'm not going to be
只要把它打出来我就不会
lazy environment Okay so we've got some
懒惰的环境好的 我们有一些
organization in our scene so that as we
在我们的场景中组织 所以当我们
add and grow our scene it's not going to
添加和扩大我们的场景它不会
get too uh crazy all right so it's also
变得太疯狂 好吧 所以这也是
good that we've created collections
很好 我们已经创建了集合
because we can now use that to scatter
因为我们现在可以用它来分散
across the geometry notes so with our uh
在几何笔记上 所以我们的呃
donut here so the icing and the donut
甜甜圈在这里 所以糖衣和甜甜圈
we're going to create a duplicate and uh
我们将创建一个副本 嗯
this is going to be the variant with the
这将是带有
long sprinkles so shift D and then hit X
长洒 所以按Shift D 然后按X
to move it along the uh x axis so let's
让它沿着x轴移动 所以让我们
just place next to it and then clicking
只需放置在它旁边 然后单击
your icing you can see we've got the
你的糖霜 你可以看到 我们有
modify stack that we've uh we created
修改我们呃我们创建的堆栈
the geometry nodes on and if we were to
上的几何体节点 如果我们
start tweaking this and make this look
开始调整这个 让这个看起来
like long sprinkles it would apply to
就像长长的洒水一样 它适用于
this one over here because we can see
这个在这里 因为我们可以看到
that little number next to it and that
它旁边的那个小数字和那个
number if you hover over it I think we
数字 如果你在上面停留 我想我们
mentioned it before but displays the
之前提到过 但显示了
number of users sharing this data so any
共享此数据的用户数 因此
change you make to this is going to be
你对此所做的改变将是
reflected on that one um so if we click
回想一下那个 嗯 如果我们点击
the two button it's now independent so
这两个按钮现在是独立的 所以
we'll now have two different versions so
我们现在有两个不同的版本
the one on the left the one the original
左边的那个是原来的那个
one let's call that round sprinkles and
让我们称它为圆形喷洒和
the one on the right let's call that one
右边的那个我们就叫它吧
long brain fart for a second there long
在那里放长脑屁一秒钟
sprinkles okay and now with that object
好的 现在用那个物体
selected let's go back to the geometry
已选择 让我们回到几何体
nodes tab okay all right so make sure
节点选项卡好的 所以请确保
you're looking at the right object make
您看到的是正确的对象制造
sure it's the the one with long
当然 就是那个长着的
sprinkles in the name and if we were to
在名字上撒上一些 如果我们要
start editing here we would have one we
在这里开始编辑 我们会有一个我们
we would have made one big mistake and
我们会犯一个大错误 然后
it would it's because this is actually
会的 因为这实际上是
not the long sprinkles node setup we
不是我们设置的长散布节点
click the pin button remember that the
单击别针按钮 请记住
pin means it's always going to be there
PIN意味着它将一直在那里
even if it's another object with a
即使它是另一个具有
different geometry node setup so
不同的几何体节点设置为
remember yeah it's a common mistake you
记住 是的 这是一个常见的错误
always do it you forget you've got pin
总是这样做 你忘了你有别针
on and you start changing things and it
当你开始改变事情的时候
does the wrong one so make sure you're
是不是做错了所以要确保你是
looking at the one that has long
看着那个已经很久的人
sprinkles in the name okay so the bit
洒在名字里 好的 所以有点
the bit that obviously matters the most
显然最重要的一点
is this this bit where it goes into our
这是不是就是我们的
instance on points node and we've
实例 并且我们已经
currently got it connected to a sphere
目前已将其连接到球体上
so I mean you could change that to
所以我的意思是你可以把它改成
another object but that won't help us
另一件物品 但那帮不了我们
because we've got more than one object
因为我们有不止一个物体
we want to scatter four different
我们想要分散四个不同的
objects across it so we can delete that
对象 这样我们就可以删除它
and instead just drag from your outliner
而只需从您的大纲视图中拖动
don't just uh if if you click on it um
不要只是呃如果你点击它
oh yeah yeah if you click off it it's
哦 是的 是的 如果你点击它 它就是
just going to disappear so make sure you
只是要消失 所以要确保你
don't do it uh you've clicked the icing
不要这样做 呃 你已经点击了锦上添花
but you need to click and drag into your
但您需要单击并拖动到您的
node setup and now it's got a collection
节点设置 现在它有了一个集合
info node rather than object info node
信息节点而不是对象信息节点
drag that into your instance input and
将其拖到实例输入中 然后
nothing happened it has actually
什么都没发生--事实上
happened but it's off center in a weird
发生了 但它偏离了中心 在一个奇怪的
place why is it doing that it's because
它为什么要这么做是因为
of the way 3D software handles data it's
3D软件处理数据的方式
now doing it on its like Global or local
现在在类似全球或本地的ITS上进行
position not Rel relative to anyway it
位置不是相对的 无论如何它
doesn't matter all what you need to do
不管你需要做什么
is check three boxes whenever you use
是不是每次使用时都勾选三个框
collections to scatter separate reset
集合分散单独重置
children now it's on the mesh correctly
孩子们 它现在正确地出现在网格上
and then it's you can see it's actually
然后你可以看到它实际上是
using all four of them on each point so
在每一点上都使用了这四个元素
then you click pick instance and now
然后您可以点击拾取实例 现在
it's going to use one of those not all
它将使用其中的一个 而不是全部
four of them together okay so it's good
四个人在一起 好的 很好
it's uh it's using it but what's going
它 呃 它正在使用它 但是发生了什么
on well the reason reason this one was
关于这一次的原因
easier with its round sprinkles is that
更容易的是它的圆形洒水
the rotation of the objects didn't
物体的旋转并没有
matter because it was round now that we
很重要 因为它现在是圆的 我们
have long sprinkles you can see the
有长长的点缀 你可以看到
rotation matters and it's currently
轮换很重要 目前
screwed up so how do we fix that the
搞砸了 那我们怎么弥补呢
first way well yeah there's a number of
第一种方法 嗯 是的 有很多
things you need to do to make it work
你需要做的事情才能让它发挥作用
correctly you you'll see is uh we want
正确地说 你会看到 呃 我们想
to take the rotation of the face so the
将面的旋转设置为
face of this these mesh here we want it
面对这个 这些网眼 我们想要它
to affect the objects right so we take
以正确地影响对象 所以我们采取
the output of our distribute points on
我们在上分配点输出
faces the rotation of that and drag it
面对它的旋转并拖动它
into the rotation input of the instances
到实例的旋转输入中
and now you can see it's having some
现在你可以看到它有一些
effect it's still not right but that is
效果还是不对 但那是
because these
因为这些
sprinkles are currently just pointed
洒水目前只是指向
upwards so it thinks okay well you want
向上 所以它认为好的 好 你想要的
to point them all outwards anyways to
无论如何 都要把它们都指向外面
fix that I mean you could fix it a
修好它 我是说你可以修好它
number you could actually fix it in
你实际上可以把它固定在
Geometry noes this is simpler so if we
几何学不 这更简单 所以如果我们
just rotate those sprinkles along the x
只需沿x方向旋转这些洒水即可
axis so RX right and then we just want
轴向右RX 然后我们只想
to to lie them down flat so essentially
从本质上说 让他们平躺在地上
90° you could type in 90° or holding
您可以输入90°或按住
down control we'll move it in 5°
向下控制 我们将把它移动5°
increments okay so 90 and then do a
增量可以 所以是90 然后做一个
single
单人
click okay so why has that not worked
点击OK 为什么这不起作用呢
well it's because as I mentioned before
这是因为就像我之前提到的
when you're scaling or rotating things
当你在缩放或旋转物体时
it's not actually saved to the object so
它实际上并未保存到对象中 因此
to apply it you have to go control a and
要应用它 你必须去控制一个和
then say rotation now that we've done
然后说轮换 现在我们已经完成了
that it's worked correctly all right so
它工作正常 好的 所以
now you can see what I said by uh to do
现在你可以看到我说的要做的事了
a lot to make it work correctly um the
让它正确地工作有很多东西 嗯
rotation is working but it's not doing
旋转起作用了 但没有起作用
what you would expect and that's because
你所期待的 那是因为
geometry nodes are so flexible you have
几何体结点非常灵活 您可以
to tell it exactly what you want to do
准确地告诉它你想做什么
we want actually random rotation so
我们实际上想要随机旋转 所以
around each of the points we don't want
围绕着我们不想要的每一个点
to each have the exact same rotation we
每一个都有完全相同的旋转
need to randomize it so for that if you
需要将其随机化 因此如果您
want to tweak the rotation on anything
想要在任何东西上调整旋转
between this point here on this uh
在这一点上呢
dotted Blue Line let's just move that
虚线蓝线 让我们把它移动
out the way uh we need to add shift a
另外 我们需要加班次a
utility
实用程序
rotation rotate not Ula Oiler that yes I
旋转旋转不是乌拉加油器那是我
know they went with the weird
我知道他们选择了怪异的
pronunciation I think it was a Frenchman
发音我想是个法国人
right could be German doesn't matter
对的 可能是德国人 没关系
same same right just to annoy all the
同样的权利 只是惹恼了所有
Europeans um anyways rotate Oiler and
欧洲人 嗯 无论如何 轮流加油器和
we're just going to drop it on that line
我们就把它放在那条线上
till it lines up okay so nothing's
直到它排好队 所以什么都不是
happened currently but with this we
目前发生了 但有了这个 我们
could change the rotation of our
可能会改变我们的
sprinkles up here but you'll notice that
洒在这里 但你会注意到
as you rotate it's kind of weird it's
当你旋转的时候 它有点奇怪
not the rotation that you would expect
不是你所期望的轮换
for each point it's the relative to the
对于每个点 它都是相对于
actual object as a whole right which
实际客体作为一个整体的权利
just means we need to change from object
只是意味着我们需要从对象改变
to local and now as you move it around
到本地 现在当你移动它的时候
you can see we're able to rotate those
你可以看到我们能够旋转这些
sprinkles but again it's not changing
洒了几下 但它又一次没有改变
the RO like randomizing it it's giving a
RO喜欢随机化它给了一个
solid value so to randomize it if we
所以要随机化它 如果我们
drag out of the rotate by input and then
按输入拖出旋转 然后
type in random it'll bring up uh this
随意输入 就会弹出这个
and we're looking for random value Val
我们正在寻找随机值Val
click and now we get this
点击 现在我们将看到以下内容
ooh so this node looks kind of scary
哦 所以这个节点看起来有点吓人
right it's got a whole bunch of
好的 它有一大堆
different values in it and it says
不同的价值观 上面写着
vector and it's very very foreign it's
它是非常非常外来的 它是
actually easy to understand it from a
实际上很容易从一个
float uh point of view with with the
漂浮的观点呢与
random value if it's in a float State
如果它处于浮动状态 则为随机值
it's going to generate a value from zero
它将从零开始生成一个值
to one on each point so if you've got
每一分都是一分 所以如果你有
like 10 points one of them is going to
他们中的一个人会得到10分
be like 015 one is going to be like 092
一个人将会像092一样
and one's you know whatever when it's in
一种是 你知道 当它进入
Vector State it's the exact same thing
向量状态 这是完全相同的事情
you've got Min and you've got Max but
你有Min和Max 但是
there are three values and the reason
它有三个价值观和原因
for that is that there are three axes
因为它有三个轴
there's the x axis there's the y axis
这是x轴 这是y轴
and there's the Zed
还有ZED
axis and same here right so you're able
轴和这里一样 所以你可以
to Define what type of rotation on each
定义每个对象上的旋转类型
axis so if we set both uh by the way if
所以如果我们同时设置 呃 顺便说一句 如果
you want to change multiple values at
您希望在以下位置更改多个值
once in blender um you can just click
一旦进入搅拌机 你只需点击
and drag down and then you can uh change
然后往下拖 然后你就可以
all of them so we set all of them to
所有人 所以我们将他们都设置为
zero and uh now you could see this
零 现在你可以看到这个
bottom one is going to be the Zed
垫底的将是ZED
because it's XY Z it doesn't tell you
因为它是XY Z 它不会告诉你
like I don't know because it's Vector
好像我不知道 因为这是向量
math I guess it's there's other areas of
数学 我猜还有其他领域
PL anyway but this this is the Zed axis
但这是ZED轴
if we increase this one you can see
如果我们增加这个 你可以看到
that's the main one that we want to
这是我们想要的主要问题
change right because that's the one that
向右转 因为这就是
makes uh the most difference now you
现在最大的不同是你
might also know looking at this you're
可能也知道看着这个你是
probably thinking like okay well we need
可能会想 好吧 我们需要
to rotate it by 360° so we would set
将其旋转360度 以便我们可以设置
this to 300 60 but you can see they're
这是300 60 但你可以看到他们是
more than rotating fully already so what
不仅仅是已经完全旋转了 那又如何
value is this exactly this is radians oh
值的正是这个 这就是弧度哦
just to get real so radians degrees
只是为了变得真实 所以弧度
actually like I had to ask chat gbt
实际上 就像我不得不问聊天GBT一样
before I recorded this what's the
在我录这个之前 什么是
difference radians are more mathematical
差弧度更数学化
and easier for mathematical equations uh
对数学方程式来说也更容易了
it's uh it's the
这是 呃 这是
circumference of Pi No 2 pi is the
圆周率2pi是圆周率
circumference look obviously I don't
周长看起来很明显我不是
know um but what I'm trying to tell you
你知道 但我想告诉你的是
is it's you just need double pi to to
是不是你只需要双倍的圆周率
make it 360° which is
变成360度 也就是
actually to to make it really
实际上是为了让它真的
complicated it's to so double Pi so Pi
把PI翻一番很复杂 所以PI
is uh
是不是
3142 to is double that and uh anyways
3142美元是这个数字的两倍 而且不管怎样
you get the idea so you can type in to
你得到了这个想法 这样你就可以输入到
and it'll actually give you the correct
它实际上会给你提供正确的
value so that's 360° rotation um we also
价值 这是360度旋转 嗯 我们也
want it cuz you can see this is the
想要它 因为你可以看到这是
other axes like the the middle one
其他的轴 像中间的那个
spinning around so we also want it on
转来转去 所以我们也想要它
that one cuz we've got a curved one so
因为我们有一个弯曲的 所以
let's make that towel and then this top
我们先做毛巾 然后做这件上衣
one is the X which is actually going to
一个是X 它实际上是
make it like wonky like so these will be
把它弄得像摇摇晃晃的 这样这些就会
like seesing up so if you increase that
比如向上看 所以如果你增加它
that's where it gets crazy and you don't
这就是事情变得疯狂的地方 而你不会
really want to use that um you do want a
真的想用那个 嗯 你确实想要一个
little bit though because it it would
尽管有一点 因为它会
make sense if they're sprinkles they're
如果它们是星星点点就说得通了
not going to be completely flat you're
你不会是完全平坦的
going to have some variance where like
会有一些变化 比如
some bit has absorbed into the icing at
有一小部分已经吸收到糖霜中了
a different angle than another but just
一个不同的角度 但只是
not too much essentially or else it
本质上不是太多 否则就是
starts to look like uh like little
开始看起来呃像个小孩子
marshmallows or whatever all over it um
棉花糖或其他什么东西 嗯
but guys that's roughly it that's the
但伙计们 就是这样 这是
hard work that was I mean I know that
努力工作 我是说 我知道
was very technical but it was really it
是非常技术性的 但它真的是
was just two notes rotate Oiler set it
只是两个音符轮流加油吗？
to local and then this random value and
到局部 然后这个随机值和
we're changing that to rotate and we did
我们正在将其改为轮换 我们做到了
it we got nice looking rotation now one
如果我们现在有一个漂亮的轮换
thing we do have to change is
我们必须要改变的是
the distance Min so because these longer
最小的距离是因为这些更长
sprinkles obviously are bigger then the
显然 喷洒的水滴比
distance Min has to change as well so we
距离民也必须改变 所以我们
can change that to something that makes
可以把它改变成某种能让
sense let's go
理智 我们走吧
04 H that might have actually been
04H 实际上可能是
pretty perfect let's try
非常完美 让我们试一试
three three's got a little bit oh
三三有一点哦
actually you know what the other thing I
实际上你知道的另一件事是我
again looking at reference I like those
再看一下参考资料 我喜欢那些
big chunky looking sprinkles so I want
看起来又大又胖的糖粉 所以我想
these to be bigger so we could you know
这些要大一些 这样我们才能你知道
alter the scale of the actual sprinkles
更改实际洒水的比例
but we're working with geometry nodes
但我们使用的是几何体节点
and we've actually got a scale value
我们实际上得到了一个比例值
right here so we could change it here
就在这里 所以我们可以在这里改变它
just as easily so the scale dragging
就像拖拽天平一样容易
down and again there's not just one
一次又一次 不止一次
value there's three axis so XY Z so drag
值有三个轴 所以XY Z所以拖动
down on all
所有人都倒下了
1.5 is going to give us some nice big
1.5会给我们带来一些不错的大
chunky looking sprinkles and now this
胖乎乎的小点心 现在又来了这个
distance value needs to be a lot bigger
距离值需要大得多
so let's go
所以我们走吧
06 that's actually pretty good I I'm
这其实挺好的我我是
getting pretty good at nailing it no no
变得相当擅长于解决问题不不
no I was right before there's always
不 我是对的 在那之前
going to be some overlap right you're
会有一些重叠 对吧 你是
not going to be able to stop it cuz it's
不能阻止它 因为它
it's not look doing object like
它看起来不像在做物体
collisions it's nothing like that it's a
碰撞根本不是那样的 而是一种
very simple again it's doing a point and
非常简单 它做了一个要点
then it's creating a radius around it
然后它会围绕它创建一个半径
and if you do the correct amount which
如果你做的量正确
for this is probably something like this
因为这可能是这样的
then it looks way too predictable and
那么它看起来太可预测了
boring which we don't want so uh 0.6
无聊 我们不想那么呃0.6
looks pretty good for me with a scale of
对我来说看起来相当不错 规模为
1.5 for these and that is it um I was
1.5对于这些 就是嗯 我是
going to put in the uh random color in
要放入呃随机的颜色
this part of the tutorial but I think
教程的这一部分 但我认为
we've gone over already so join me in
我们已经过去了 请加入我吧
the next part and we will finally add
下一部分 我们最终将添加
some color to our sprinkles and make
给我们的洒上一些颜色并制作
this look nice so join me in the next
这个看起来不错 所以下一个和我一起吧
part
部分